Rachele Lang

O Denver, CO

→ ramlang@proton.me

→ ramlang.github.io

→

PROFILE

I'm a full stack software engineer proficient in TypeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, and Golang based in Denver, Colorado. I recently created Campfire, a self-hosted deploy preview tool. I'm excited to apply my technical experience and non-technical skills to solving new problems.

EXPERIENCE

Creator & Software Engineer, Campfire

2024 – present

Campfire is an open-source, self-hosted CI/CD development tool for automating deploy previews. It has a built-in UI that supports syncing of comments with GitHub.

- Architected a stack template (CloudFormation) to provision Campfire's AWS infrastructure (VPC, Application Load Balancer, Lambda, S3, IAM roles) through the CLI reducing over 40 steps to one command.
- Automated containerized app deployment and teardown on AWS (ECR, ECS) using GitHub Actions.
- Extended session replay recording capabilities with iframes using a custom built SDK.
- Designed a RESTful API facilitating serverless backend communication with Campfire UI (AWS API Gateway, Lambda, S3, Secrets Manager).
- Configured manifest for GitHub App installation to make requests to GitHub's API on behalf of any user.
- Built a minimalist user-friendly UI using React and Material UI and implemented unit testing.
- Authored technical case study of Campfire's problem domain, architecture, and engineering choices.
- Collaborated with a remote team of four engineers by performing daily standups, pair-programming, and coordinating across four different time zones.

Software Engineer, Self-employed

2021 - 2024

List of open-source and personal projects:

- Rainbucket Tool for inspecting and debugging webhooks (Node.js, Nginx, React, Express, WebSockets, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Digital Ocean Droplet)
- Travel Expenses App tracks expenses and sorts by category, city, or country (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL)

Teaching Assistant, Launch School

2022 - 2023

- Conducted over 80 live-coding interview assessments and gave detailed feedback on student's performance.
- Graded over 100 written assessments on the programming fundamentals of Ruby and JavaScript.
- Provided thorough code reviews of student projects identifying bugs, correcting syntax, and evaluating code structure.
- Led weekly study groups on basic Ruby programming concepts to prepare students for technical assessments.

Client Services Representative, Excelchem Laboratories, Inc.

2018 - 2020

An environmental and microbiological testing laboratory with a primary focus on soil and water analysis.

- Improved coordination between client services and lab team through constant communication of client expectations.
- Reviewed work orders in Laboratory Information Management System to identify potential errors
- Documented standard operating procedures for report uploads to client specific databases.

SKILLS

Back-end

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, Golang, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud

AWS (ALB, CloudFormation, ECR, ECS, IAM, Lambda, S3), Digital Ocean Droplets, Heroku

Front-end

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Handlebars, jQuery, Material UI, HTML, CSS

Other

Git/GitHub, Linux, Nginx, Docker, Bash, Jest, Minitest, OOP, WebSockets, REST APIs, Postman

EDUCATION

Launch School ☑ 2021 – 2023

Multi-year mastery-based curriculum for software engineering.